Ronak Kogta

Interests

Operating Systems, Performance Optimization

Projects

A Few good sequences for HLS compilers [Jan-May 2013]

We present a practical approach to find good optimization sequences for hls genererated hardware on per-program basis.

Docklock [2014]

Zero-knowledge Docker Containers to provide one extra layer of security in cloud based hosting.

Firefox OS Synchronization APIS [2014-15]

I worked with Firefox OS to create synchronization api layers to seamlessly sync data across multiple devices per application.

RAMFs: A simple volatile filesystem [Completed]

In this project, we used FUSE to implement a filesystem in userspace, which was designed to use virtual memory space for all operations

Pedestrian Detection [Independent Project, July 2010]

In this project, we used HOG/SIFT descriptors of an image to detect humans in images, with the use of linear SVM learning model. The goal was to build power-efficient detection system, and come up with good features of images

Work Experience

Openwall Summer of Security [Summer 2013]

Here, I worked on improving John the ripper support for AES encryption on OpenCL platform. Before that I worked on low level description of opencl code, and ways to tweak with it

Research Assistant at CVEST Lab [2011-2013]

Teaching Assistant [2011-2013]

- 1. Head TA, Operating Systems 2013
- 2. Head TA, Computer Networks 2012
- 3. TA, Modern Computer Architecture 2011

Build Engineer, **RENIAC Inc.** [2013-2014]

OS Engineer, Mozilla Foundation [2014-2015]

+91 9959064260

ronak.kogta@research.iiit.ac.in

http://researchweb.iiit.ac.in/ ronak.kogta/

Education

2011 – 2013 Master of Science

Parallel Algorithms, Computer Arch.

CVEST, IIIT Hyderabad

2007 – 2011 Bachelor of Technology

Computer Science *IIIT, Hyderabad*

Achievements

2014,2015 Winner of Local session of Docker

Global Hackathon II & III

2010 Got an Scholarship for International

Congress of Mathematicians

Skill Set

Operating System *GNU/Linux*

Languages C, C++, Python, bash, golang

Environment Vim, Eclipse, Emacs

Libraries CUDA, OpenCL, OpenMP, Intel TBB

Research

Workshop HeMPA 2011, Hyderabad

MSR Winter School for TCS, Hyderabad, 2012

Posters Workshop in Hybrid Algorithms

HiPC 2011, On Eigen Value computation

using MPI for GPU and CPU

Papers Retargeting Optimization Sequences from

Scalar Processors to FPGAs in HLS

compilers [FPGA 2015]

Hobbies

Books I like books on philosophy and fantasy,

and read manga

Others I like to run and listen

to instrumentals